# M Usman Maqbool **Bhutta**

#### PHD CANDIDATE · DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONIC AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Room 2008 (25), Robotics Institute, 2nd Floor, CYT Building, Lift(35-36), HKUST

□ (+852) 609-44-786 | 💌 mumbhutta@connect.ust.hk | 🎢 usmanmaqbool.github.io | 🛅 usmanmaqbool | 🖏 usman17888

"Do it with passion or not at all."

## **Summary** \_

Current co-founder and COO of Lisee Technology Corporation. 5+ years experience specializing in project management for research and development, web development and marketing at Friends Corporate Technologies. I have been a part of some other startups related to real estate, marketing, and automation. A super nerd who loves entrepreneurship, deep learning, and enjoys to develop the idea to reality. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises..

## **Work Experience**

#### **INDUSTRY**

#### **Lisee Technology Corporation Limited**

Central, HK

COO Jan 2018 - Present

- Won funding support for company | TSSSU Support HK\$ 300,000 (Jun 19 May 20).
- Indoor Navigation for Libray using Lisee Technology | PCF Support HK\$ 160,000 (Jun 18 May 19).

#### **Friends Corporate Technologies**

Islamahad PK

**CEO** Feb 2013 - Aug 2015

50+ Projects | Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing, Web Applications Development, MVC Applications

#### **Federal Government of Pakistan**

Islamabad, PK

SCIENTIFIC OFFICER May 2012 - Feb 2013

Electronics/ Electrical Engineering, R&D, image processing

### Server4Sale, LLC

Islamabad, PK

PHP Developer Dec 2009 - Mar 2010

Php web application development for Joomla and Zend frameworks.

#### **ACADEMIC**

## **Department of Computer Science**

BZU sub campus Sahiwal, PK

LECTURER (VISITING)

Feb 2016 - Jun 2016

Teaching MCS and BS-CS courses

#### **Department of Physics**

Government PG College Sahiwal, PK

Teaching BS physics (Electronics related courses + Labs + Projects)

## **Education**

#### The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology - HKUST

(Kowloon, Hong Kong)

Ph.D. Candidate, Department of Electronic & Computer Engineering

Sep. 2016 - Present

Aug. 2015 - Apr. 2016

- Got PEEF Pakistan scholarship to pursuing my studies
- Research interests; Multi-Agent SLAM System, Deep Learning for automation industry and autonomous car driving

#### Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.PHIL. ELECTRONICS, DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRONICS

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

· Research: Signal and Image Processing

Mai. 2010 - Juli. 2012

• Grade: 1st Division (80% Marks)

## Quaid-i-Azam University - QAU

Islamabad, Pakistan

M.Sc. Electronics, Department of Electronics

Mar. 2010 - Jun. 2012

• 2nd position in batch

• Grade: 1 st Division (74.6% marks)

B.Sc. in Mathematics and Physics

• Grade: 1st Division

## **Research Publications**

#### Multiple Lane Detection Algorithm Based on Optimised Dense Disparity Map Estimation

Conference Paper

Han Ma, Yixin Ma, Jianhao Jiao, M Usman Maqbool Bhutta, Mohammud Junaid Bocus, Lujia Wang, Ming Liu, Rui Fan Accepted in IEEE International Conference on Imaging Systems and Techniques (IST) 2018

Oct 2018

## PCR-Pro: 3D Sparse and Different Scale Point Clouds Registration and Robust Estimation of Information Matrix For Pose Graph SLAM

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA, MING LIU

Jul 2018

Presented in IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and Intelligent Systems, and won **Best Student Paper Finalist Award.** 

## An intelligent approach for robust detection and recognition of multiple color and font styles automobiles license plates: A feature-based algorithm

Conference Paper

M USMAN MAQBOOL BHUTTA, HASAN MAHMOOD, AND HAROON MALIK

Jul 2014

Published in IEEE International Conference on Audio, Language and Image Processing (ICALIP).

#### **Efficient Reset Design Techniques**

Journal Paper

QAMAR, ZOHA, BUSHRA YASEEN, AND USMAN MAQBOOL

2015

Published in Science International Lahore

## Honors & Awards

#### INTERNATIONAL

July. 2018	Best Student Paper Finalist Award, IEEE Int. Conf. on CYBER Technology in Automation, Control, and	Tianjin, China
	Intelligent Systems	riarijiri, Criiria
May, 2018	Best Proposal Audience Award, Campus Challenge - Transportation, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Nov, 2017	Best Mapper Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
May, 2017	Completion Award, The Graduate Teaching Assistant Training, HKUST	HKUST, HK
Dec, 2016	Best External Award, Robotics and Multi-Perception Lab, HKUST	Shenzhen, China
Nov, 2016	Completion Award, Author Workshop, Elsevier Publishing Campus	HKUST, HK

#### DOMESTIC

DOMESTIC				
Sep 2013	<b>Participant,</b> Painting for peace (Pakistan-India-Afghanistan) event, a part of the Harmony initiative	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	Participant, Case Spark in business plan competition	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	Participant, Case EPICA	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	<b>Participant</b> , How to be a Better Playwright Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK		
Oct 2012	Participant, Punjab Youth Festival	Lahore, PK		
Oct 2011	Participant, Int'l Youth Conference and Festival	Islamabad, PK		
Sep 2011	Participant, Asian Youth Conference and Peace Festival	Lahore, PK		
Apr 2011	<b>Completion Award</b> , Acting and Directing Theater Workshop by PNCA and US Embassay Pakistan	Islamabad, PK		
Dec 2011	Participant, National Drama Festival	Islamabad, PK		
Dec 2010	<b>Instuctor of short Course</b> , PHP Web Development' at the Department of Electronics, QAU	Islamabad, PK		
Apr 2013	<b>Completion Award</b> , Running River Rafting course by Adventure Foundation of Pakistan	Mansehra, PK		
Apr 2013	Completion Award, Paragliding course by QAU Adventure Club	Islamabad, PK		
Dec 2008	Award of Honor, Finance Secretary of Electronics Student Society (ESS) at QAU	Islamabad, PK		

## **Academic Activities**

Spr 2019	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
2019	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	IROS 2019
Fall 2018	Teaching Assistant, ELEC4820 - Medical Imaging	HKUST, HK
2018	Referee Service, IEEE/RSJ International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems	IROS 2018
Spr 2018	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , EESM 5547 - Multimedia Signal Processing	HKUST, HK
Spr 2017	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , ELEC 1010 - Electronic and Information Technology	HKUST, HK